MIN SHIN KHANT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

I am a self-taught software engineer with a keen insight into innovative design and a strong understanding of technology for the best user experience. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team. Strong attention to detail and ability to finish projects on schedule and within budget.

SKILLS

- Skillful in Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, ReactJS, NodeJS, Flask, Django, AWS, Git
- Proficient in 3D Modeling, 3D Printing, Soldering and Assembling Electronic Components
- Experienced knowledge of Microcontrollers, VSCODE, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, SOLIDWORKS and Fusion360
- Exposure to the C++, C and Java
- Native in Burmese, Fluent in English, Beginner in German

PROJECTS

CoSources

A website where available programming learning resources are ranked and discussed, is built with Django Frameworks and SQLite3.

Paparazi

A website using the Machine Learning model from "Clarifai" API is to recognize the image of a celebrity and provide the name.

COVID-19 Dashboard

A dashboard in progress to provide the plausible correlation between COVID-19 cases and Weather, using Django, Heroku, weatherAPI, COVID-19 API and SQLite.

Superhero Search

A search web app created using ReactJS with superheroAPI where you can search all the superheros ever existed including Rambo and James Bond.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hardware Engineer

Kodiak Engineering | Oct 2018 to Present

- Design and develop computer hardware and support peripherals.
- Build, test, and modify product prototypes using working models or theoretical models constructed with computer simulation.

Assembly Engineer

BotFactory, Inc. | May 2019 to Feb 2020

- Examine products to verify conformance to quality standards.
- Operate machinery used in the production process, or assist machine operators.
- Record information such as the number of products tested, meter readings, and dates and times of product production.

College Assistant

CUNY BMCC | Aug 2018 to Feb 2020

- Assist students for registering for classes and to enroll for school and aid with students to get financial aid.
- Resolve student issues by interacting with different departments such as Admission, Financial Aid Office, Bursar Office and Registrar Office which lead to student satisfaction.

EDUCATION

CUNY Borough of Manhattan Community College

Associate Degree in Engineering Science (GPA - 3.9)

- Enrolled since Jun. 2016 to Jan 2019
- Engineering Honor Student of 2018
- President of BMCC Robotics Club
- Dean's List of Borough of Manhattan Community College
- BMCC Foundation Scholarship
- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

CREDENTIALS

- Django for Everyone Specialization Coursera
- The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery
- Complete Python Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery2020
- Complete Python Bootcamp: From Zero to Hero in Python
- Data Science and Machine Learning with Python Codecademy Computer Science Career Path
- Certificate of Participation at BMCC Annual Research Symposium (BARS)
- Certificate of Participation at Mathematical Association of America 2019

Cell: 917-294-8602 Email: minshinkhant@gmail.com LinkedIn: @minshinkhant Github: @minshinkhant Address: 1297 Saint Johns Place, Brooklyn, New York, 11213